<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>My Reflections</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on My Reflections</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 13:17:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://av1nash.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 19:02:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/about/</guid><description>Hey! I am Avinash I&amp;rsquo;m a data architect based out of Charleston, South Carolina.
I work at Blackbaud as a Senior BI Developer.
I write about data, machine learning, azure and other Microsoft technologies.</description></item><item><title>Maslow&#39;s Hierarchy of Needs</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/maslowhierarchy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 13:17:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/maslowhierarchy/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Regex to remove html tags</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/regexhtml/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:13:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/regexhtml/</guid><description>I was working on a problem which required some string data cleanup, the string I was working with had categorical values of survey response - satisfied, dissatisfied, very satisfied etc. but with html tags embedded in the string.
1 &amp;lt;img src=&amp;#34;https://organization123.surveycompany.com/CP/Graphic.php?IM=ABC&amp;#34; style=&amp;#34;width: 41px; height: 39px;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/img&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;Very Satisfied I was only interested in the user rating part and wanted to get rid of all the html tags. In this quest to remove html tags I stumbled upon some very helpful stackoverflow posts which used regular expressions to remove html tags.</description></item><item><title>Suez Canal in the time of COVID-19</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/suezcanal/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 23:53:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/suezcanal/</guid><description>I doubt if any individual or industry on this planet is unaffected by the Coronavirus pandemic (hence a pandemic duh!). In this post I wanted to share some interesting facts I learned by following the news trail about oil prices.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start with what happened to oil prices in April 2020. A little background on Oil trading is necessary to grasp the full picture, so here we go:
Oil is traded on its future price.</description></item><item><title>Annual Percentage Yield</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/apy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 22:15:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/apy/</guid><description>Annual percentage yield1 measures the total amount of interest paid on an account based on the interest rate and the frequency of compounding.
$$APY=100[(1 + \frac{interest}{principal})^{\frac{365}{days in term}} -1]$$
$$interest = principal[(\frac{APY}{100} + 1)^{\frac{days in term}{365}} -1]$$
So when a bank advertises that a savings account with them will earn 1.50 % APY, that&amp;rsquo;s the interest rate, frequency of compounding is usually 365 days or 1 year and principal is the amount you will choose to deposit with them.</description></item><item><title>Principle of least astonishment</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/pola/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 16:23:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/pola/</guid><description>From Wikipedia:
Principle of least astonishment (POLA), also called the principle of least surprise states that a component of a system should behave in a way that most users will expect it to behave; the behavior should not astonish or surprise users.
Examples: In Windows operating system, when you hit &amp;ldquo;F1&amp;rdquo; on keyboard it usually opens the help for that particular program, if you created a program which instead closed the window - it will astonish the users of your program and should be redesigned according to the principle of least astonishment.</description></item><item><title>System uptime</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/system-uptime/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 23:50:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/system-uptime/</guid><description>High Availability is the property of a system which measures its uptime. When you measure your system&amp;rsquo;s uptime and are confident that no matter what, at minimum your system remains up x hours per year you can offer it as a commitment to the users of your system by signing a SLA (Service-level agreement)
System uptime is usually expressed as three nines, four nines or five nines. You can translate it into uptime or downtime hours per year by multiplying it with the total number of hours in a year (8760).</description></item><item><title>Streisand Effect</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/streisand-effect/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 14:26:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/streisand-effect/</guid><description>Psychological reactance From Wikipedia:
Psychological reactance is &amp;ldquo;an unpleasant motivational arousal that emerges when people experience a threat to or loss of their free behaviors.&amp;rdquo; An example of such behavior can be observed when an individual engages in a prohibited activity in order to deliberately taunt the authority who prohibits it, regardless of the utility or disutility that the activity confers.
Streisand effect is an example of psychological reactance, wherein once people are aware that some information is being kept from them, they are significantly more motivated to access and spread that information.</description></item><item><title>VS Code snippets</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/vscode-snippets/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 22:24:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/vscode-snippets/</guid><description>VS Code snippets are templates that make it easier to enter repeating code patters.
You can have both language specific code snippets and global snippets. To create your own snippets, go to File &amp;gt; Preferences &amp;gt; User Snippets.
Select a language, let&amp;rsquo;s say I want to create a snippet for markdown pages, so I will select markdown. Then add following code and save the file.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 { &amp;#34;File Header&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;prefix&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;header&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;description&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Output a file header for a hugo blog post&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;body&amp;#34;: [ &amp;#34;---&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;title: $TM_FILENAME&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;date: $CURRENT_YEAR-$CURRENT_MONTH-$CURRENT_DATE $CURRENT_HOUR:$CURRENT_MINUTE:$CURRENT_SECOND&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;toc: true&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;autoCollapseToc: true&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;draft: false&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;comment: true&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;tags: []&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;categories: []&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;---&amp;#34;, ] } } You might also in this case want to make some changes in your user settings (File &amp;gt; Preferences &amp;gt; Settings) to enable this newly added snippet.</description></item><item><title>Very simple Git workflow</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/simple-git-workflow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 12:20:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/simple-git-workflow/</guid><description>Simple git workflow
Open command prompt and go to your local copy of your repository.
1 cd C:\Workplace\DevOps\reponame\ Create new branch.
1 git checkout -b user/avinash-addNewPackage Make your changes to the local copy of repository.
Stage your changes
1 git add * Commit your changes.
1 git commit -m &amp;#34;Adding new package&amp;#34; Push your changes to remote branch.</description></item><item><title>Running MS SQL on Linux in AKS</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/mssql-on-linux-aks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 14:53:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/mssql-on-linux-aks/</guid><description> Creating a kubernetes cluster Login to you azure account 1 2 3 ```sh az login ``` Create resources 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 ```sh #Create a resource group az group create --name rgACR --location eastus #Create an Azure container registry instance az acr create --resource-group rgACR --name dockerSQL2019 --sku Basic #Log in to the container registry az acr login --name dockerSQL2019 #Create an AKS cluster az aks create --resource-group rgACR --name sqlAKSCluster --node-count 2 --generate-ssh-keys --attach-acr dockersql2019 #To configure kubectl to connect to your Kubernetes cluster az aks get-credentials --resource-group rgACR --name sqlAKSCluster #To verify the connection to your cluster kubectl get nodes #Create an SA password in the Kubernetes cluster kubectl create secret generic mssql --from-literal=SA_PASSWORD=&amp;#34;ComplexPassword&amp;#34; ```</description></item><item><title>Databricks Cheatsheet</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/databricks-shortcut/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 12:18:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/databricks-shortcut/</guid><description>General Shortcut Description Ctrl + / Multiline comment Cmd + / Toggle line comment Shift + Enter Run command and move to next cell Spark Dataframe Shortcut Description df.head() returns first few rows of a dataframe df.count() returns count of non null values of all columns in a dataframe df.</description></item><item><title>Understanding payments processing stack</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/understanding-payments-layercake/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 12:18:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/understanding-payments-layercake/</guid><description>[text1] [text2] [text3]</description></item><item><title>Summing a Geometric Series</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/summing-a-geometric-series/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 11:56:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/summing-a-geometric-series/</guid><description>As is the nature of internet, I was reading something and one thing lead to another. When my conscious mind took over, I was staring at a page talking about Geometric Series, to be precise this page Mailchimp - Summing Geometric Series. Its been a while since I read something in Mathematics domain, so to exercise my brain, I thought of reading and following along with the explanation. Since I am making a conscious effort to record things more diligently, this is my attempt to understand the text.</description></item><item><title>How-to find and remove hidden characters in a database table</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/mssql-find-and-remove-hidden-chars/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/mssql-find-and-remove-hidden-chars/</guid><description>When working with large text fields (usually they come from fields which allow users to enter free text in front end or email body etc.) it is possible to encounter data which has invisible characters. These characters could be invisible to your eyes in management studio while querying or to certain functions like - LTRIM, RTRIM or in a predicate condition like -
1 WHERE([ColumnName]) &amp;lt;&amp;gt; &amp;#39;&amp;#39; You can try a brute force method to resolve this by replacing commonly occuring invisible characters like -</description></item><item><title>Counting rows in T-SQL</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/mssql-counting-rows/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/mssql-counting-rows/</guid><description>One can count number of rows in a table in many ways and depending upon the chosen option results may or may not be same.
Reason being the way SQL handles NULL while counting. Following are three different ways to COUNT number of rows in a table:
Query Results SELECT COUNT(*) returns total row count SELECT COUNT(1) returns total row count SELECT COUNT([Col Name]) returns row count where [Col Name] IS NOT NULL</description></item><item><title>Finding Prime numbers using T-SQL</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/mssql-finding-primenumbers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/mssql-finding-primenumbers/</guid><description>This is a problem I found on Hacker Rank. I did not had a clue how I can solve it in MS SQL, I mean I know what the logic of finding a prime number is but how do I apply that to MS SQL.
Then I came across this solution from a user rodbourn and this is an absolutely amazing SQL query, every line is a concept in itself and I thought I will dissect it to understand it and maybe help someone else in the process.</description></item><item><title>How-to set up VS tools for R-Services</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/setting-up-vstools-for-rservices/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/setting-up-vstools-for-rservices/</guid><description>I am trying to follow this course Introduction to Microsoft R Server but with the exception that I wanted to run the R script on my SQL Server R Services (in database) rather than Microsoft R Client. This required making following changes:
Specifying path of R Engine in VS RTool.
Open RTools Options and specify the path to your Rserver folder (default in case of SQL Server 2016 is C:\Program Files\Microsoft SQL Server\130\R_SERVER) 2.</description></item><item><title>How-to Setup MS Sql server R-services</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/setup-sqlserver-rservices/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/setup-sqlserver-rservices/</guid><description>MSDN Article here explains in detail the steps required to set up SQL Server R Services (In-Database). For those who have already installed R Services as part of their SQL Server 2016 installation (like me) and looking for enabling the R services, you can open SQL Server management studio and run following command:
1 2 Exec sp_configure &amp;#39;external scripts enabled&amp;#39;, 1 Reconfigure with override Open services.msc and restart SQL Server services.</description></item></channel></rss>