<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tutorial on My Reflections</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/categories/tutorial/</link><description>Recent content in tutorial on My Reflections</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 22:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://av1nash.github.io/categories/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Extract Google Analytics data using Reporting API - Part 1</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/google-analytics-reportingapi-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/google-analytics-reportingapi-1/</guid><description>This is a two part tutorial to teach how you can extract google analytics data using Reporting API.
In the first part, we will be covering some prerequisite setup which will allow us to leverage Reporting API.
Create a new project by logging into your google API console
Click on Credentials under side menu, select CONFIGURE CONSENT SCREEN Under User Type select External While configuring OAuth consent screen, you just need to profide Application name and support email.</description></item><item><title>Counting rows in T-SQL</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/mssql-counting-rows/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/mssql-counting-rows/</guid><description>One can count number of rows in a table in many ways and depending upon the chosen option results may or may not be same.
Reason being the way SQL handles NULL while counting. Following are three different ways to COUNT number of rows in a table:
Query Results SELECT COUNT(*) returns total row count SELECT COUNT(1) returns total row count SELECT COUNT([Col Name]) returns row count where [Col Name] IS NOT NULL</description></item><item><title>Finding Prime numbers using T-SQL</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/mssql-finding-primenumbers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/mssql-finding-primenumbers/</guid><description>This is a problem I found on Hacker Rank. I did not had a clue how I can solve it in MS SQL, I mean I know what the logic of finding a prime number is but how do I apply that to MS SQL.
Then I came across this solution from a user rodbourn and this is an absolutely amazing SQL query, every line is a concept in itself and I thought I will dissect it to understand it and maybe help someone else in the process.</description></item></channel></rss>