<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>explanation on My Reflections</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/categories/explanation/</link><description>Recent content in explanation on My Reflections</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 20:37:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://av1nash.github.io/categories/explanation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Error message using Azure data lake store destination in SSIS</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/adls-ssis-orc/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 20:37:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/adls-ssis-orc/</guid><description>To be able to interact with Azure services using SSIS, you need to install SSIS feature pack for Azure
But even after installing service pack, if you are using Azure Data Lake store destination with file formats - ORC or Parquet, you&amp;rsquo;ll get this error message:
Error message:
[Azure Data Lake Store Destination [2]] Error: System.Exception: Java SE is required to use ORC format.
Solution as mentioned in the link above is to install Java SE Runtime environment as its a pre-requisite/dependency.</description></item><item><title>Tabula rasa Vs Innatism</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/tabularasa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:11:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/tabularasa/</guid><description/></item><item><title>P/E Ratio</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/pe-ratio/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 20:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/pe-ratio/</guid><description>Definition Price-to-earnings ratio or P/E of a company measures its current share price relative to its per-share earnings (EPS). Source: Investopedia
$$ P/E \,ratio = {Share \,price \over Earnings \,per \,share} $$
Significance Let&amp;rsquo;s calculate P/E ratio of a fictional company Avi Corp. which is trading currently at $100 per share. Their EPS (Earnings per-share) is $20, making their P/E ratio = 100&amp;frasl;20 = 5.
This can be interpreted as - &amp;ldquo;investors are willing to pay $5 for every $1 of company&amp;rsquo;s earnings&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Suez Canal in the time of COVID-19</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/suezcanal/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 23:53:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/suezcanal/</guid><description>I doubt if any individual or industry on this planet is unaffected by the Coronavirus pandemic (hence a pandemic duh!). In this post I wanted to share some interesting facts I learned by following the news trail about oil prices.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start with what happened to oil prices in April 2020. A little background on Oil trading is necessary to grasp the full picture, so here we go:
Oil is traded on its future price.</description></item><item><title>Annual Percentage Yield</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/apy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 22:15:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/apy/</guid><description>Annual percentage yield1 measures the total amount of interest paid on an account based on the interest rate and the frequency of compounding.
$$APY=100[(1 + \frac{interest}{principal})^{\frac{365}{days in term}} -1]$$
$$interest = principal[(\frac{APY}{100} + 1)^{\frac{days in term}{365}} -1]$$
So when a bank advertises that a savings account with them will earn 1.50 % APY, that&amp;rsquo;s the interest rate, frequency of compounding is usually 365 days or 1 year and principal is the amount you will choose to deposit with them.</description></item><item><title>Summing a Geometric Series</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/summing-a-geometric-series/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 11:56:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/summing-a-geometric-series/</guid><description>As is the nature of internet, I was reading something and one thing lead to another. When my conscious mind took over, I was staring at a page talking about Geometric Series, to be precise this page Mailchimp - Summing Geometric Series. Its been a while since I read something in Mathematics domain, so to exercise my brain, I thought of reading and following along with the explanation. Since I am making a conscious effort to record things more diligently, this is my attempt to understand the text.</description></item></channel></rss>