<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>how-to on My Reflections</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/categories/how-to/</link><description>Recent content in how-to on My Reflections</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:01 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://av1nash.github.io/categories/how-to/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How-to find and remove hidden characters in a database table</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/mssql-find-and-remove-hidden-chars/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/mssql-find-and-remove-hidden-chars/</guid><description>When working with large text fields (usually they come from fields which allow users to enter free text in front end or email body etc.) it is possible to encounter data which has invisible characters. These characters could be invisible to your eyes in management studio while querying or to certain functions like - LTRIM, RTRIM or in a predicate condition like -
1 WHERE([ColumnName]) &amp;lt;&amp;gt; &amp;#39;&amp;#39; You can try a brute force method to resolve this by replacing commonly occuring invisible characters like -</description></item><item><title>How-to set up VS tools for R-Services</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/setting-up-vstools-for-rservices/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/setting-up-vstools-for-rservices/</guid><description>I am trying to follow this course Introduction to Microsoft R Server but with the exception that I wanted to run the R script on my SQL Server R Services (in database) rather than Microsoft R Client. This required making following changes:
Specifying path of R Engine in VS RTool.
Open RTools Options and specify the path to your Rserver folder (default in case of SQL Server 2016 is C:\Program Files\Microsoft SQL Server\130\R_SERVER) 2.</description></item><item><title>How-to Setup MS Sql server R-services</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/setup-sqlserver-rservices/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/setup-sqlserver-rservices/</guid><description>MSDN Article here explains in detail the steps required to set up SQL Server R Services (In-Database). For those who have already installed R Services as part of their SQL Server 2016 installation (like me) and looking for enabling the R services, you can open SQL Server management studio and run following command:
1 2 Exec sp_configure &amp;#39;external scripts enabled&amp;#39;, 1 Reconfigure with override Open services.msc and restart SQL Server services.</description></item></channel></rss>