<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>how-to on My Reflections</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/categories/how-to/</link><description>Recent content in how-to on My Reflections</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:13:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://av1nash.github.io/categories/how-to/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Regex to remove html tags</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/regexhtml/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:13:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/regexhtml/</guid><description>I was working on a problem which required some string data cleanup, the string I was working with had categorical values of survey response - satisfied, dissatisfied, very satisfied etc. but with html tags embedded in the string.
1 &amp;lt;img src=&amp;#34;https://organization123.surveycompany.com/CP/Graphic.php?IM=ABC&amp;#34; style=&amp;#34;width: 41px; height: 39px;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/img&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;Very Satisfied I was only interested in the user rating part and wanted to get rid of all the html tags. In this quest to remove html tags I stumbled upon some very helpful stackoverflow posts which used regular expressions to remove html tags.</description></item><item><title>VS Code snippets</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/vscode-snippets/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 22:24:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/vscode-snippets/</guid><description>VS Code snippets are templates that make it easier to enter repeating code patters.
You can have both language specific code snippets and global snippets. To create your own snippets, go to File &amp;gt; Preferences &amp;gt; User Snippets.
Select a language, let&amp;rsquo;s say I want to create a snippet for markdown pages, so I will select markdown. Then add following code and save the file.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 { &amp;#34;File Header&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;prefix&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;header&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;description&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Output a file header for a hugo blog post&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;body&amp;#34;: [ &amp;#34;---&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;title: $TM_FILENAME&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;date: $CURRENT_YEAR-$CURRENT_MONTH-$CURRENT_DATE $CURRENT_HOUR:$CURRENT_MINUTE:$CURRENT_SECOND&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;toc: true&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;autoCollapseToc: true&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;draft: false&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;comment: true&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;tags: []&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;categories: []&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;---&amp;#34;, ] } } You might also in this case want to make some changes in your user settings (File &amp;gt; Preferences &amp;gt; Settings) to enable this newly added snippet.</description></item><item><title>How-to find and remove hidden characters in a database table</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/mssql-find-and-remove-hidden-chars/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/mssql-find-and-remove-hidden-chars/</guid><description>When working with large text fields (usually they come from fields which allow users to enter free text in front end or email body etc.) it is possible to encounter data which has invisible characters. These characters could be invisible to your eyes in management studio while querying or to certain functions like - LTRIM, RTRIM or in a predicate condition like -
1 WHERE([ColumnName]) &amp;lt;&amp;gt; &amp;#39;&amp;#39; You can try a brute force method to resolve this by replacing commonly occuring invisible characters like -</description></item><item><title>How-to set up VS tools for R-Services</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/setting-up-vstools-for-rservices/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/setting-up-vstools-for-rservices/</guid><description>I am trying to follow this course Introduction to Microsoft R Server but with the exception that I wanted to run the R script on my SQL Server R Services (in database) rather than Microsoft R Client. This required making following changes:
Specifying path of R Engine in VS RTool.
Open RTools Options and specify the path to your Rserver folder (default in case of SQL Server 2016 is C:\Program Files\Microsoft SQL Server\130\R_SERVER) 2.</description></item><item><title>How-to Setup MS Sql server R-services</title><link>https://av1nash.github.io/post/setup-sqlserver-rservices/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://av1nash.github.io/post/setup-sqlserver-rservices/</guid><description>MSDN Article here explains in detail the steps required to set up SQL Server R Services (In-Database). For those who have already installed R Services as part of their SQL Server 2016 installation (like me) and looking for enabling the R services, you can open SQL Server management studio and run following command:
1 2 Exec sp_configure &amp;#39;external scripts enabled&amp;#39;, 1 Reconfigure with override Open services.msc and restart SQL Server services.</description></item></channel></rss>